Daniele Mingolla

ANALYST DEVELOPE

Milan, Italy

1998 | ■ danielemingollabusiness@gmail.com | ★ danielemingolla.github.io

danielemingolla | daniele-mingolla



SUMMARY

I currently work as a development analyst at Lutech. Parallel to my university studies, I worked as an online retailer and as a promoter, two experiences that allowed me to acquire excellent problem solving and team working skills. I recently obtained the Microsoft Azure Administrator Associate certification and I continue to independently study neural networks and the main Machine Learning algorithms applied to text analysis. I aim at continuous improvement as fast as possible.

WORK EXPERIENCE

LutechCologno Monzese, Italy

ANALYST DEVELOPER, FIELD: DAI - ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

July 2020 - Present

September 2018 - December 2018

- Definition of the implementation and deployment phases of the solution.
- Development of the different modules of the application (code writing).
- Verification of the implemented functionalities, to ensure the correct integration into the complex environment and in accordance with the user/customer needs.
- Documentation of development phases and test results.

Ebay Perugia, Italy

• Market and competition analysis for the choice of products to sell through our page on Ebay.

- Selection of suppliers based on parameters such as shipping speed and quality of the product supplied.
- · Creation of the graphics to be included in the product description and to be advertised on the main social networks.

Sintesi Promotions S.R.L Perugia, Italy

PROMOTER April 2018 - May 2018

· Setting up of various stands for the presentation to customers of products belonging to different brands.

EDUCATION.

PRIVATE SELLER

UNIVERSITY OF PERUGIA Perugia, Italy

Bachelor in Computer Science September 2017 - July 2020

Vote: 110L

IISS "PACINOTTI-FERMI"

Taranto, Italy

DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER SCIENCE September 2012 - July 2017

Vote: 100

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

Microsoft Milan, Italy

Azure Administrator Associate

August 2020 - August 2022

The Azure Administrator Associate certification validates the skills and knowledge related to the management of cloud services such as:

- · Manage Azure subscriptions and resources.
- · Implement and manage storage.
- Deploy and manage virtual machines (VMs).
- Configure and manage virtual networks.
- · Manage identities.

eForHum Milan, Italy

JUNIOR MICROSOFT CLOUD SYSTEM AND NETWORK ENGINEER

System training on Microsoft Cloud technologies and on premises Windows networking on Cisco Systems technology. In parallel to the theoretical study, many consolidation laboratories were carried out. Specifically, the Go Deploy platform was used for the Windows Server and Microsoft Azure laboratories, while for the Networking part, the Cisco Packet Tracer software was used.

- Deploying and Managing Windows Server, Managing Active Directory, DHCP, DNS, IPv6, Local Storage, Group Policy, Server Virtualization con Hyper-V.
- Ethernet, Network Layer, IP Addressing, Routing Concepts, Dynamic Routing, VLANs, NAT (IPv4).
- Azure Administration, Virtual Machines, Azure Storage, Virtual Networking, Intersite Connectivity, Monitoring, Network Traffic Management, Azure Active Directory, Securing Identities, Governance e Compliance, Data Services.

IISS "PACINOTTI-FERMI"

Taranto, Italy

CCNA ROUTING AND SWITCHING

September 2016 - July 2017

February 2020 - May 2020

The course provides a comprehensive and structured knowledge of networking technologies including fundamentals of IP routing and switching, network security and network services.

- Network fundamentals.
- · IP connectivity.
- · Security fundamentals.

Edinburgh Language Academy

Edinburgh, Scotland

TRINITY COLLEGE LONDON - GRADE 7

September 2015 - October 2015

PERSONAL PROJECTS_

Review classifier

NEURAL NETWORK ABLE TO ANALYZE THE TEXT OF HOTEL REVIEWS AND CLASSIFY SENTIMENT.

February 2020 - July 2020

Articlee

OPEN-SOURCE PLATFORM THAT OFFERS USERS THE POSSIBILITY TO WRITE AND SHARE THEIR ARTICLES WITH THE COMMUNITY.

August 2019 - November 2019

Investment strategy

THE STRATEGY IS BASED ON CAPITAL DIVERSIFICATION THROUGH INVESTMENT IN 7 DIFFERENT PASSIVELY MANAGED FUNDS.

February 2019 - March 2020